<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd"[]>
<concept id="concept_06F2D37060A542A6B8B11AC460796360">
  <title>Prerequisites for Standard Implementation</title>
  <shortdesc>
    <?xm-replace_text Short Description?>
  </shortdesc>
  <prolog>
    <metadata>
      <keywords>
        <keyword>Heartbeat Video</keyword>
        <keyword>Video Analytics</keyword>
      </keywords>
      <othermeta name="solution" content="Analytics" />
      <othermeta name="topic" content="Developer and implementation" />
    </metadata>
  </prolog>
  <conbody>
    <section id="section_ajb_xlk_mbb"><title>Audience Manager Enablement</title><p>Adobe Audience
        Manager (AAM), a Data Management Platform (DMP), helps you bring your audience data assets
        together, making it easy to collect commercially relevant information about site visitors,
        create marketable segments, and serve targeted advertising and content to the right
        audience. </p><p>With AAM, you are not tied to a data seller, exchange, or demand-side
        platform. Additionally, AAM is completely agnostic when it comes to your partners’ data
        assets. With access to multiple data sources, AAM offers digital publishers the ability to
        use a wide variety of third-party data and our private data co-op. </p><p>To learn more
        about AAM, see <xref
          href="https://marketing.adobe.com/resources/help/en_US/aam/c_am_overview_intro.html"
          format="html" scope="external">Audience Manager Overview</xref>. </p><b>Video Heartbeat
        Data in Audience Manager</b><p>For both video content and video ads, the metrics and
        metadata that are collected by using solution (reserved) variables can be automatically sent
        to AAM. The data transfer is available across all platforms including desktop, mobile, and
        OTT. To enable this server-side data transfer, you need to reach out to Adobe Client Care
        and ask for this feed to be enabled. </p><p>Federated Data fully supports data sharing to
        AAM. Please work with your Adobe team for confirmation of Federated Data settings.</p><note
        type="important">To ensure the smooth transfer of data to AAM, you should be on the latest
        versions of the heartbeat libraries. </note></section>
    <section id="section_zsh_fhk_mbb">
      <title>Marketing Cloud Enablement</title>
      <p>As part of the requirements to implement the Video Heartbeat SDK, you need to implement the
        Marketing Cloud ID Service (formerly known as Visitor ID Service). </p>
      <p>The Marketing Cloud ID service enables the common identification framework for the
        Marketing Cloud Core Services, solutions, and customer attributes and audiences in the
        People core service. It works by assigning a unique, persistent ID to a site visitor. When
        your organization implements the ID service, this ID lets you identify the same site visitor
        and their data in different Marketing Cloud solutions. </p>
      <p>
        <fig id="fig_E7648D1E230E4AA588C80C9092B662EA">
          <image href="graphics/mc_id_service_graphic.png"
            id="image_37FA5A24D7D94E1D925A60E342CA9612"/>
        </fig>
      </p>
      <p>The ID service can also replace the different solution-specific IDs (for example, Analytics
        AID). Through the <xref
          href="https://marketing.adobe.com/resources/help/en_US/mcvid/mcvid-authenticated-state.html"
          format="html" scope="external">Customer IDs and Authentication States</xref>
        functionality, the ID service lets you pass in your own customer IDs to the Marketing Cloud.
        Keep in mind, however, that the ID service only works with the solutions to which you have
        already subscribed. If you are not signed up for access to other products, the ID service
        does not provide the access. </p>
      <p>Going forward, the ID service is an integral component of many current and future Marketing
        Cloud features, enhancements, and services. Currently, the ID service supports <xref
          href="http://www.adobe.com/marketing-cloud/web-analytics.html" format="html"
          scope="external">Analytics</xref>, <xref
          href="http://www.adobe.com/marketing-cloud/data-management-platform.html" format="html"
          scope="external">Audience Manager</xref>, and <xref
          href="http://www.adobe.com/marketing-cloud/testing-targeting.html" format="html"
          scope="external">Target</xref>. </p>
      <note type="important">To participate in the Adobe Marketing Cloud Device Co-op, the Marketing
        Cloud ID service required. </note>
      <p>If you have not implemented the ID service, now is the time to start considering a
        migration strategy. For more information about the importance and role of the ID service,
        see <xref
          href="http://blogs.adobe.com/digitalmarketing/analytics/why-new-adobe-marketing-cloud-id-service-should-be-on-your-radar/"
          format="html" scope="external">Why the Marketing Cloud ID Service Should be on Your
          Radar</xref>. </p>
      <note type="important">In the absence of any user ID information present on the video specific
        calls the default analytics <xref
          href="https://marketing.adobe.com/resources/help/en_US/sc/implement/visid_fallback.html"
          format="html" scope="external">Fallback ID Methods</xref> will apply. </note>
      <p>For more information about the Marketing Cloud ID, see <xref
          href="https://marketing.adobe.com/resources/help/en_US/mcvid/mcvid-overview.html"
          format="html" scope="external">Overview</xref>. </p>
      <p>For more information about implementing the Marketing Cloud ID Service, see <xref
          href="https://marketing.adobe.com/resources/help/en_US/mcvid/" format="html"
          scope="external">Marketing Cloud ID Service</xref>. </p>
    </section>
    <section id="section_ibc_fhk_mbb">
      <title>Analytics Enablement</title>
      <p>To enable video reports in Analytics and see the video and video ad data you are
        collecting, see <xref
          href="c_vhl_vid-rept_enable.xml#concept_4D5798BE986342C4838DBD8E5662AAE7" format="dita"
          scope="local"><?xm-replace_text Video Reports Enablement?></xref>. </p>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>