<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept_ADA4B5C612D24280955BD0B7E79B4271"> 
  <title>Measuring Video in Adobe Analytics</title> 
  <shortdesc>
  </shortdesc> 
  <conbody> 
	 <note type="important"> The video documentation provided here is specific to clients utilizing
			version 1.5 or higher of Adobe's Video Analytics SDK for heartbeat measurement, and does
			not include instructions around the legacy milestone video implementation. We encourage
			all customers to move towards adopting the latest Video Analytics SDK to capitalize on
			the improvements and expanded measurement. You can view the <xref
				href="video_overview.xml#concept_ADA4B5C612D24280955BD0B7E79B4271/section_cnj_5st_p1b"
				format="dita" scope="local">benefits of transitioning to the SDK</xref> below. While
			Adobe will continue to support the Milestone method of tracking videos, there will not
			be any planned updates, fixes or feature improvements. Please reach out to your Adobe
			Account Manager if you have any further questions. </note> 
	 <section id="section_8BFE4F8DA64B4A5F826A4940B11AA466"> 
		<title>Overview</title> 
		<p>Adobe Analytics for Video (Video Analytics) is an add-on to the base Analytics offering that
				provides clients with robust video measurement for content, audio and
				advertisements. Video Analytics provides many benefits to customers to allow for
				real-time monitoring, detailed analysis, actionable insights and monetization
				opportunities. Video tracking is enabled through SDK integrations with the most
				commonly used video players. The latest SDKs have the additional capability of
				capturing audio related metrics. </p> 
		<p>Adobe Analytics for Video enables clients to track the full customer
		  journey across their site, which includes video consumption, and these measures
		  are easily integrated into Analytics reporting and other Experience Cloud
		  products. Video measurement allows you to slice and dice your data into
		  multiple dimensions and segments, capturing all of the metadata you need to do
		  a full detailed analysis, and to attribute success criteria to fully viewed
		  videos, average time spent and completed ads.
		</p> 
		<p> The video solution not only measures vital video delivery metrics
		  related to QoS, such as dropped frames, time spent buffering, and average
		  bitrate, but it can also be combined with your website or app data to visualize
		  the flow of the customer and their interests to better be able to make
		  recommendations and personalize their experiences through the Adobe Experience
		  Cloud.
		</p> 
	 </section> 
	 <section id="section_7712BA90EAE64C118218D1C581EF68B7"> 
		<title>Benefits</title> 
		<p>Some of the many benefits that Adobe's video solution provides
		  include:
		</p> 
		<ul id="ul_hj1_k4t_p1b"> 
		  <li id="li_F1990DF6A34947A2ADC50EE36F707264"><b>Timely analysis</b> -
			 Make real-time, actionable decisions utilizing key video performance metrics
			 (e.g., duration) across multiple channels. Video events are measured in 
			 <b>10-second</b> intervals to capture all activity as it occurs.
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_8A588D150CA948F59AD681F58B3FB1E1"><b>Drive engagement</b> -
			 Fully engage users through fewer buffering events and by understanding where
			 and when ads should display within video content to provide a smooth, less
			 intrusive viewing experience that brings users back and delivers repeat visits.
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_1D569128684F4005872C3B55BE9385C0"><b>Holistic picture</b> -
			 Combine multiple data points across all of your content distributors to get a
			 full view of all your video activity, and measure engagement and views across
			 all possible channels through 
			 <xref href="federated-analytics.xml" scope="local" format="dita"/>.
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_1FE0FDC8A5F4401A87371BECD6545F4F"><b>Increased
				granularity</b> - Evaluate viewing behavior at the most granular level,
			 including individual visitor time of day, concurrent viewers by minute, and
			 average duration the content was viewed.
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_8DC065EFCE4547218C491130F18A86E7"><b>Precise measurement</b>
			 - Measure across the multiple devices used for video consumption, including
			 OTT, smartphone, tablet, desktop, and more, to monitor user engagement patterns
			 and habits.
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_B0C3245D5FCF4C179DE2F86BC6F47A63"><b>Segmentation</b> -
			 Apply classifications to your players, devices, genres, chapters, and shows to
			 see how each has an impact on your overall views and customer engagement with
			 content, audio, ads, and combined.
		  </li> 
		</ul> 
		<draft-comment author="kenny"> 
		  <p>Here is how video and video ad data flow into Adobe: 
		  </p> 
		  <p> 
			 <fig id="fig_5A574F71C807481B8E1D66335CB836F3"> 
				<image href="graphics/how_aa_video_works.png"
				 id="image_D3A97A67B8AF4055B6BF72F92190E18B"/> 
			 </fig> 
		  </p> 
		</draft-comment> 
	 </section> 
	 <section id="section_cnj_5st_p1b"> 
		<title>Heartbeat versus Milestone Benefits</title> 
		<p>Adobe Analytics for Video is able to be measured through two means:
		  the legacy Milestone method and the current Heartbeats method. The Heartbeats
		  method is the preferred method of measurement and we encourage all clients to
		  move to this version if they haven’t already, to take advantage of the benefits
		  described below. 
		</p> 
		<p>The legacy Milestone method is based on individual server calls to the Analytics server, for
				video starts, quartiles, duration, and completes. The Heartbeats method provides a
				more robust video tracking solution that measures video in 10 second intervals to
				provide enhanced, standardized video metrics. In addition, Adobe has derived
				learnings from our Milestone method to provide a smoother, streamlined
				implementation process through the Video Analytics SDK utilized by heartbeats. </p> 
		<p>Some of the many benefits of the Heartbeats method include:
		</p> 
		<ul id="ul_t1g_ytt_p1b"> 
		  <li id="li_267FB0CAD3AA44D69349D492A8220A59"><b>Streamlined
				implementation process</b> - Map variables more easily through your player API
			 and validate implementations through the Adobe Debug Tool to ensure all the
			 necessary variables are tracked accurately.
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_6C95299F3CAC4ABAAE785807F40E71C3"><b>Automatic Adobe
				Experience Cloud Integration</b> - Take advantage of the automatic integration
			 with the Adobe Experience Cloud through the Marketing Cloud ID, segment your
			 video audiences, target them, and make video recommendations based on user
			 preferences.
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_73D452ED5D55468A91D2DD6470787409"><b>Shared video data
				through Federated Analytics</b> - Capitalize on our industry-first video
			 sharing capabilities, to evaluate data holistically across all of your video
			 distribution partners—operators, programmers, and distributors. 
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_CFEAB938F1F34A429528451D5222C9E6"><b>Partnerships with
				Certified Ratings Partners</b> - Adobe partners with audience ratings partner
			 Nielsen to provide neutral census third party measurement to allow for trusted,
			 certified video ratings.
		  </li> 
		  <li id="li_CE5D00A03C144561ABFD766FA8E8BB40"><b>Standardized solution
				across all platforms</b> - Enable consistent, standardized variables across all
			 of your videos and platforms to allow for a more efficient cross-campaign,
			 device and vendor comparison.
		  </li> 
		</ul> 
		<p> 
		<table id="table_mmx_f5t_p1b"> 
		<title><b>Comparison Chart</b></title> 
		<tgroup cols="3"> 
		  <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1"/> 
		  <colspec colnum="2" colname="col2"/> 
		  <colspec colnum="3" colname="col3"/> 
		  <thead>	
			 <row> 
				<entry/> 
				<entry><b>Video Analytics - Milestone</b>
								</entry> 
				<entry><b>Video Analytics - Heartbeats</b>
								</entry> 
			 </row> 
		  </thead> 
		  <tbody> 
			 <row> 
				<entry><b>Video Events</b>
				</entry> 
				<entry>High-level Standard Events
				</entry> 
				<entry>Detailed and Custom Events every 10s
				</entry> 
			 </row> 
			 <row> 
				<entry><b>Metrics and Dimensions</b>
				</entry> 
				<entry>Variances among Vendors, Non-Standardized Metrics and
				  Dimensions
				</entry> 
				<entry>Clear, Standardized Metrics, Dimensions, and Benchmarks
				  across Vendors
				</entry> 
			 </row> 
			 <row> 
				<entry><b>Integrations w/ Adobe Products</b>
				</entry> 
				<entry>Individual Sessions w/ some Mappings and Integrations
				</entry> 
				<entry>Stitched Marketing Cloud ID linked to full Adobe Experience
				  Cloud for easier cross-analysis
				</entry> 
			 </row> 
			 <row> 
				<entry><b>Pricing</b>
				</entry> 
				<entry>Tracked and billed against each server call
				</entry> 
				<entry>Transparent tracking by video stream (single)
				</entry> 
			 </row> 
			 <row> 
				<entry><b>Implementation and Support</b>
				</entry> 
				<entry>Longer integrations with limited support on legacy versions
				  &amp; no upgrades
				</entry> 
				<entry>Streamlined configuration with ongoing updates and
				  improvements
				</entry> 
			 </row> 
			 <row> 
				<entry><b>Partner Sharing</b>
				</entry> 
				<entry>N/A
				</entry> 
				<entry>Federated Analytics and Certified Metrics
				</entry> 
			 </row> 
			 <row> 
				<entry><b>Advanced Tracking</b>
				</entry> 
				<entry>N/A
				</entry> 
				<entry>Error Recovery Tracking and Concurrent Viewers
				</entry> 
			 </row> 
		  </tbody> 
		</tgroup> 
		</table> 
		</p> 
	 </section> 
	 <section id="section_lkm_l5t_p1b">
			<title>Devices Supported</title>
			<p>Adobe Analytics for Video has evolved with the industry to provide strong data
				collection tools to ensure each video stream is collected and reported across all
				meaningful devices. Our Video Analytics SDK is developed for all of the most
				utilized devices, including: </p>
			<ul id="ul_cyj_r5t_p1b">
				<li id="li_B3480EFBC422492B991D966BFFC49AF9">iOS and Android smartphones and tablets </li>
				<li id="li_9BB32F326F364DAD95408FD4E53779E4">OTT devices for ROKU, AppleTV, FireTV,
					and Android TV </li>
				<li id="li_F12CFAB58ED646BAB63D3C796776643B">JavaScript Browser for Desktop and
					Laptop </li>
			</ul>
			<p> The SDK’s are routinely updated when new versions of devices are released, and you
				can use these SDKs to integrate with most of the largest video players today,
				including Brightcove and Ooyala. </p> The table below provides a list of the devices
			that are currently supported through our SDK implementation or Analytics API. To
			download the most recent version of the SDK, visit <xref href="c_vhl_download-sdks.xml"
				scope="local" format="dita"/>. If there is a device that is not listed which you are
			seeking measurement against, please contact customer care or your solution consultant
			for the status of that device. <table id="table_znx_dvt_p1b">
				<tgroup cols="3">
					<colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" align="left" colwidth="1*"/>
					<colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" align="center" colwidth="1.08*"/>
					<colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" align="center" colwidth="1.19*"/>
					<tbody>
						<row>
							<entry/>
							<entry align="center"><b>Adobe Video SDK</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"><b>Video Analytics Collection API</b>
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><b>JavaScript Browser</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"><b>✔</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><b>iOS Devices</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"><b>✔</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><b>Android Devices</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"><b>✔</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><b>Windows </b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"/>
							<entry align="center"><b>✔</b>
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><b>Blackberry</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"/>
							<entry align="center"><b>✔</b>
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><b>Apple TV (new/legacy)</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"><b>✔</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><b>ROKU</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"><b>✔</b>
							</entry>
							<entry/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><b>OSX</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"/>
							<entry align="center"><b>✔</b>
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><b>Fire TV</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"><b>✔</b>
							</entry>
							<entry/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><b>Android TV</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"><b>✔</b>
							</entry>
							<entry/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><b>Chromecast</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"><b>✔</b>
							</entry>
							<entry/>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><b>Xbox 1</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"/>
							<entry align="center"><b>✔</b>
							</entry>
						</row>
						<row>
							<entry><b>Sony PS3/PS4</b>
							</entry>
							<entry align="center"/>
							<entry align="center"><b>✔</b>
							</entry>
						</row>
					</tbody>
				</tgroup>
			</table>
		</section> 
  </conbody> 
</concept>
